# **Ammar Almajed**

## Software Engineer

💌 ammaralmajed7@gmail.com 📞 +966542463848 🛚 in LinkedIn/AmmarAlmajed 👩 GitHub/AlmajedA

My Website

### **OBJECTIVE**

As a Software Engineer experienced in the full software development life cycle, I excel in writing requirements, designing architectures, development, testing, deployment, and maintenance processes. My proficiency in Object-Oriented Programming (OOP) and a strong commitment to software quality measurements enable me to deliver high-performing and scalable software solutions that meet project standards and expectations.

#### **EDUCATION**

#### King Fahd University of Petroleum and Minerals

Aug 2019 - May 2024 | Dhahran, Saudi Arabia

Bachelor of Science: Software Engineering

Cumulative GPA: 3.77 / 4.00 with First Honors.

#### **EXPERIENCE**

**Student Assistant** 

May 2023 – Jul 2023 | Dhahran, Saudi Arabia

King Fahd University of Petroleum & Minerals - KFUPM

Helping Students in Math 208 (Differential Equations & Linear Algebra)

**Exchange Student** 

Aug 2022 – Dec 2022 | Daejeon, South Korea

Korea Advanced Institute of Science and Technology

Elected to represent KFUPM in the exchange program which was held in KAIST between August 2022 to December 2022.

#### Introduction to Programming in Python Grader

Jun 2020 – Aug 2020 | Dhahran, Saudi Arabia

King Fahd University of Petroleum & Minerals - KFUPM

Correcting python and C programming assignments for more than 500 students.

#### **PROJECTS**

**CarGAN** Aug 2023 – Dec 2023

PvTorch

Developed a model that generate accurate car images using GAN architecture, with discriminator loss equal to

Benchmarking Aug 2023 - Dec 2023

Sklearn | Tensorflow | PvTorch

Develop diverse models, including SVM, NN, DT, and XGB on a dataset to measure each model performance and selecting the best model with 94% accuracy. In addition, develop an active learning mechanism that enabled the model to achieve similar levels of accuracy with less amount of data.

#### **SKILLS** LANGUAGES

#### **Technical Skills**

• Web Development:

Backend: Django | Express Frontend: Vanilla JS | Angular

- Deep Learning: PvTorch
- Virtualization: Docker
- Version control: Git
- Data science: Pandas | Matplotlib
- Programming Languages: Python | JavaScript |

## Arabic

English

TOEFL 74